So I was browsing reddit, and this new CTF for beginners popped up.
所以我在浏览Reddit和这个新的CTF 对于初学者来说。
Obviously I had to check it out and directly head to my favorite category, the binary exploitation
很明显我必须直接检查 直奔我最喜欢的类别，二进制开发
stuff.
东西。
And of course there is a server you can connect to as a regular user, and when you exploit
当然还有一个服务器可以连接 作为一个普通用户，当你利用
a challenge you will elevate privileges to another user to gain access to the secret
将特权提升到 另一个获得秘密访问权的用户
flag.
旗帜。
But the biggest challenge of all, and I couldn’t find rules that would forbid this, would be
但最大的挑战，我不能 找到禁止这样做的规则
to gain root.
生根
So let’s do that.
那我们就这么做吧。
Remember my dirty cow explanation video?
还记得我的脏母牛解释视频吗？
Let’s use the proof of concept exploit that we had there and test if it works on this
让我们利用概念证明 我们在那里测试了它是否能用在这个上面
server.
服务器。
So we can simply copy this code to a file in tmp and compile it.
所以我们可以简单地将这个代码复制到一个文件中 在tmp中编译它。
To test if we can overwrite files that don’t belong to us, without overwriting critical
测试是否可以覆盖 属于我们，不覆盖批评
root owned files, we log in as another challenge user on the system, create a file with some
根拥有的文件，我们作为另一个挑战登录 用户在系统上，创建一个文件
content.
内容。
And then we go back to the first user, execute dirty cow on that file and attempt to write
然后我们回到第一个用户，执行 那个文件上的脏母牛并试图写
some other characters to it.
还有其他一些角色。
And when we check, we can see that it works.
当我们检查的时候，我们可以看到它起作用了。
At this point I wrote the author a message on reddit to inform him that the server is
这时我给作者写了一封信 在Reddit上通知他服务器
vulnerable and he should quickly update.
易受攻击，他应该迅速更新。
But now we need a plan what root file we could overwrite to become root ourselves.
但是现在我们需要一个计划什么样的根文件我们可以 把自己改写成根。
Our restriction is, that we have to overwrite something in a file, we can’t append or
我们的限制是，我们必须重写 文件中的某些内容，无法追加或
prepend anything.
准备好任何东西。
The first obvious idea would be a setuid binary, but the issue is that in order to write a
第一个明显的想法是setuid二进制， 但问题是为了写一个
backdoor shell to the binary, we would have to parse the elf file format and figure out
后门壳到二进制，我们会 解析ELF文件格式并找出
where the entry point is.
入口点在哪里。
An easier strategy is to overwrite data in a text file.
更简单的策略是在 文本文件。
And I chose /etc/passwd.
我选择了/etc/passwd。
You can see here the user id of the users, and if we would change the uid of the pwn1
您可以在这里看到用户的用户ID， 如果我们改变pwn1的uid
user to 0, we would login as root.
用户为0时，我们将以根用户身份登录。
So.
所以。
The dirty cow proof of concept writes to the beginning of the file.
肮脏的奶牛概念证明写信给 文件的开头。
So first we have to figure out the offset inside of /etc/passwd.
所以我们首先要计算出偏移量 在/etc/passwd内部。
We can use hexdump for that and count a little bit.
我们可以用hexdump来计算一下 比特。
So pwn1 user is at offset hex 4c0 plus a little bit.
所以pwn1用户处于偏移量hex 4c0加上一点
I use python as a caluclator and modify the exploit code to write to a fixed offset.
我使用python作为calucator并修改 利用代码写入固定偏移量。
I think here would be a good plan.
我认为这是个好计划。
And you have to be very very careful with choosing these offsets and choosing what to
你必须非常小心 选择这些偏移量并选择要做什么
write, because you can screw up the whole system if you don’t.
写，因为你可以把整个事情搞砸 系统，如果你没有。
So I copy /etc/passwd to try what I want to do before doing it to the real binary.
所以我复制/etc/passwd来尝试我想要的 在对真正的二进制文件执行此操作之前先执行此操作。
And of course, my first attempt would have wrecked the system.
当然，我的第一次尝试 破坏了系统。
So adjusting the offset a bit and also appending a newline at the end is finally successful
所以调整一点偏移量，同时附加 最后一条新线终于成功了
and I write to the real /etc/passwd.
我写信给真正的/etc/passwd。
Now when we switch to pwn1 or ssh login to pwn1, we get a root shell.
现在，当我们切换到pwn1或ssh时，登录到 pwn1，我们得到一个根壳。
Then we can read out all flags.
然后我们可以读出所有的标记。
Once we are done, we revert back /etc/passwd to the original state.
完成后，我们返回/etc/passwd 到原始状态。
Some important notes.
一些重要的注释。
Be very very careful what you overwrite with an exploit like this.
非常小心用什么覆盖 像这样的剥削。
Just one byte miscalculated, and you might destabilize, crash, DoS the system or simply
只有一个字节计算错误，您可能 使系统不稳定、崩溃或简单地
lock yourself out.
把自己锁在外面。
Also if you find a server vulnerable, think about the impact or context you are in.
另外，如果您发现服务器易受攻击，请考虑 关于你所处的影响或背景。
This small private CTF server project, that is intended to be hammered is different from
这个小型的私人CTF服务器项目， 旨在锤击的不同于
a webserver you exploited from some random company.
一个你随机利用的网络服务器 公司。
So don’t go around and try this if you have no permissions or you could cause a lot of
所以，如果有的话，不要到处尝试这个。 没有权限，否则会导致
damage.
损坏。
Make an ethical decision.
做出合乎道德的决定。
Be aware of the risk you are taking.
注意你所冒的风险。
And thanks to maro for being cool about this and allowing me to make a video about it.
感谢Maro对此事的冷静 并允许我制作一个关于它的视频。
Good luck with your plattform.
祝你的鸭嘴兽好运。